Harold B. Hoskins Papers, 1822-1982: Finding Aid MC221
Public Policy Papers
Harold B. Hoskins Papers
1822-1982
Public Policy Papers
Hoskins, Harold B.
MC221
17 boxes
Harold Boies Hoskins was a businessman, diplomat, and educator working in Middle Eastern affairs. This collection consists of correspondence, diaries, notes, photographs, publications, maps, and professional files that document Hoskins' personal and professional activities, as well as the Hoskins family.
Biographical / Historical
Harold Boies Hoskins was a businessman, diplomat, and educator working in Middle Eastern affairs. Born in Beirut and raised by American missionary parents, he graduated from Hill School in 1913 and Princeton in 1917. Hoskins served in both WWI and II, and in 1942, he was commissioned by President Roosevelt to act as a U.S. diplomatic emissary in Palestine. He became a special assistant to the U.S. ambassador in Tehran in 1944, and served as a counselor for economic affairs at the American embassy in Cairo, and for American diplomatic missions in Lebanon, Palestine, Iraq, Iran, Saudi Arabia, and Ethiopia over the course of his career. From 1955 until his retirement in 1961, he served as director of the Foreign Service Institute.
Scope and Contents
The Harold B. Hoskins Papers consist of correspondence, diaries, notes, photographs, publications, maps, and professional files that document Hoskins' personal and professional activities, as well as the Hoskins family. See individual series descriptions for more specific information on each series.
Conditions Governing Access
LINKED DIGITAL CONTENT NOTE: Please note that some previously linked digital content is temporarily unavailable while the data is being migrated from an outdated access service. If you would like to access this content, please send a request to Mudd Library.
The collection is open for research use.
Custodial History
Gifted to the American Heritage Center at the University of Wyoming by Grania H. Ackley in 1991. The American Heritage Center deaccessioned the papers in November 2007. Transferred from the American Hertitage Center at the University of Wyoming in November 2007.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Scott Rodman approved the gifting to Mudd on behalf of the Hoskins family in November 2007 (accession number ML.2007.037). Grania Ackley donated eight rolls of 16mm safety film and a file of correspondence in May 2012 (accession number ML.2012.020). The materials that comprise Series 3 were donated by John and Binti Ackley in 2014 (accession number ML.2014.029).
Appraisal
Two boxes of books were separated during processing in 2007. No materials were separated from Series 3.
Missionaries.; Middle East -- Politics and government -- 1914-1945.; Middle East -- Politics and government -- 1945-; Correspondence.; Diaries.; Photographs.; Diplomacy; Middle East; American history/20th century; Foreign Service Institute U.S.
- Series 1: U.S. diplomacy career, 1900-1978; 6 boxes
  Conditions Governing Access
  LINKED DIGITAL CONTENT NOTE: Please note that some previously linked digital content is temporarily unavailable while the data is being migrated from an outdated access service. If you would like to access this content, please send a request to Mudd Library.
  The collection is open for research use.
  Scope and Contents
  The U.S. Diplomacy Career series largely focuses on Hoskins' work in Middle Eastern diplomacy, including his years as Director of the Foreign Service Institute in Beirut, and features correspondence, speeches, diaries, maps, notes, reports, publications, and reel-to-reel tapes.
  Arrangement
  No further arrangement after division into series.
  - United States Foreign Service Institute, 1900-1975; 3 folders (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
  - Speeches, 1949 November-1960 February; 1 box
    - National War College, 1949 November 1; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Council on Foreign Relations, 1950 January 10; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - National War College, 1950 December 5; 2 folders (Box 1, Folder 6-7)
    - "The Near and Middle East Economic Evolution", 1950 December 6; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - "The United States and the Problem with the Middle East", 1951 November 15; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - "Middle East Oil", 1951 November 15; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Council on World Affairs, 1951 December 1; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Council on Foreign Relations, 1952 January 31; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - "How Policy is Developed", 1952 February 29; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - World Order Week, 1952 July 22; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Foreign Policy Association, Worcester MA Branch, 1952 March 19; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Foreign Service Institute, 1953 June 23; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Cold Spring Project, 1953 August 6; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Cold Spring Project, 1953 August 13; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Cold Spring Project, 1953 August 27; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Dutchess County Council on World Affairs, 1953 November 17; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Branch of Council on Foreign Relations, Charlottesville, VA, 1953 December 9; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Vassar Club, Washington, D.C., 1953 October 10; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - School of Advanced International Studies, 1953 February 24; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - American Association of University Women, College Park Branch, 1954 January 21; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - The Middle East as World Center of Oil, 1953 August 21; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Cosmopolitan Club, New York, 1954 February 18; 2 folders (Box 1, Folder 26-27)
    - "The Ugly American Furor", 1960 February; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Letters from Feisal, Palestine and State Department, 1944; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - State Department, 1942-1944; 9 folders (Box 1, Folder 30-38)
  - "The Present Situation in the Near East", 1943 April 20; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Standard Oil Reports and Memoranda, 1947-1950; 2 folders (Box 1, Folder 40-41)
  - Bennett College, 1961 August; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Overseas Education Study, 1954 November; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Overseas Education Study, 1954 November; 3 folders (Box 2, Folder 1-3)
  - Office of Strategic Services, 1942 July 20-November 13, 2 folders (Box 2, Folder 4-5)
  - The Middle East as a Center of the World Oil, 1953; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Operations Coordinating Board, 1954; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - American University of Beirut, 1957; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Foreign Service Institute, 1952-1958; 6 folders (Box 2, Folder 9-14)
  - Publications, 1949-1967; 2 folders (Box 2, Folder 15-16)
  - Names and Gifts, undated; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Address Lists, 1966-1970; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Maps, undated; 7 folders (Box 3, Folder 3-9)
  - "Trucking Through France" Manuscript, 1917 September; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Turko-Italian War Paper, circa 1910; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Loose Notes, 1969; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Foreign Service Institute, 1943; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Foreign Service Institute, 1957-1958; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 14)
    Includes memo to Hoskins from John Foster Dulles.
  - Trips to Middle East, 1948-1950; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Trip to Middle East, 1948 September-October; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - State Department, 1951-1952; 2 folders (Box 3, Folder 17-18)
  - United States Information Agency Training, 1954-1955; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - France Trip, 1967; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - France Trip, 1969; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Signed Photograph of King Ibn Saud, undated; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Manuscripts, 1822-1982; 1 box
    - "Zionism and the American Jew", 1964; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - "Tales of UNRRA", undated; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Notes, 1822-1982; 1 box
    - 1939-1949, 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - 1943, undated, 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - 1944-1955, 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Pamphlets and Other Printed Material, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Report to Standard Oil Company, 1949; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Trip to Europe, 1963; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Report to the Operations Coordinating Board on United States Overseas Education Programs, 1954 November 9; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Report to the Operations Coordinating Board on United States Overseas Education Programs, 1954 November 9; 3 folders (Box 4, Folder 1-3)
  - Speech, "The Celestial Bed", undated; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Obituary, 1977 April 25; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1920-1969; 2 folders (Box 4, Folder 6-7)
  - Periodicals, 1953-1978; 2 folders (Box 4, Folder 8-9)
  - Department of State Transportation Service Coin, undated; 1 box (Box 4)
  - Annotated "Liste du Corps Diplomatique", 1944; 1 box (Box 4)
  - Books in Arabic, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 4)
  - Transcript of "Notes"- Harold B. Hoskins Trip, 1949 March-April; 1 box (Box 4)
  - Anglo-American Committee of Inquiry: Report to the United States Government and His Majesty's Government in the United Kingdom, 1946 April 20; 1 box (Box 4)
  - Annual Reports Board of Managers: Syrian Protestant College, 1866-1902; 1 box (Box 4)
  - Published Documents, 1822-1982; 1 box
    - U.S. Foreign Service Institute, Spoken German, undated; 3 folders (Box 4, Folder 10-12)
    - U.S. Foreign Service Institute, 1943-1966; 4 folders (Box 4, Folder 13-16)
  - Pamphlets and Printed Material, 1947-1966; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Professional Correspondence, 1913-1972; 1 box
    - Le Blan, Emile, 1933; 5 folders (Box 5, Folder 1-5)
    - W.C. Eberle Overseas Corporation, 1955; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - American University of Beirut, 1969; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Europe Trip, 1971; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Cooke, Goodwin and France Trip, 1971-1972; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Concerning Franklin E. Hoskins' book, "Nile to the Nebo", 1913; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Weizman, Chaim, 1943 June 12; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Foreign Service Institute Senior Officer Graduation Ceremonies, undated; 1 tape reel-to-reel tape (Box 12, Tape 1)
  - Unidentified Audio, undated; 1 tape reel-to-reel tape (Box 12, Tape 2)
- Series 2: Personal Papers, 1822-1982; 8 boxes
  The Personal Papers series includes correspondence, notes, diaries, photographs, and other materials relating to Hoskins travels, his time at Hill School and Princeton, and his service in both World Wars. Also included are correspondence, diaries, photographs, and scrapbooks that document several members of the Hoskins family, including his parents, Franklin Evans Hoskins and Harriet E. Hoskins, and their time as missionaries in Syria in the late 19th through early 20th century.
  - Diaries, 1822-1982; 3 boxes
    - Eddy, Mary P., New Testament Miniature Book, undated; 1 box (Box 5)
    - Harold B. Hoskins Diaries, 1899-1965; 1 box (Box 5)
      School years, World War II and travels.
    - Rev. Franklin E. Hoskins Princeton Diary, 1882-1883; 1 box (Box 5)
    - 1929, 1931-1964, 1 box (Box 6)
    - 1965-1982, 1 box (Box 7)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1822-1982; 3 boxes
    - World War I, 1915-1918; 4 folders (Box 8, Folder 1-4)
    - Marine Corps, 1918-1920; 2 folders (Box 8, Folder 5-6)
    - Hoskins, Grania O'Malley, 1927-1928; 5 folders (Box 8, Folder 7-11)
    - Hoskins, Franklin E, 1888-1920; 6 folders (Box 8, Folder 12-17)
    - Hoskins, Harriette E, 1929-1930; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Hoskins, Grania O'Malley, 1944; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Hoskins, Grania O'Malley, 1977; 3 folders (Box 8, Folder 20-22)
    - General, 1923-1928; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Hoskins, Franklin E, 1884-1897; 2 folders (Box 8, Folder 24-25)
    - Hoskins, Harriette to family, 1928; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Hoskins, Harriette. to Hoskins, Harold, undated; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - General, 1956-1971; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Condit, A. to Condit, Harriett W, 1822 January; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - To "Mother" from "Tuchey", 1882 October 20; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - From Hill School, circa 1910; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Nigeria Visit, 1965; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Letter from County Cork, Ireland, 1940 September 18; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Family Letters and Postcards, 1875-1974; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Hoskins to Mr. and Mrs. O'Malley Knott, 1944-1945; 2 folders (Box 13, Folder 1-2)
      Immediate Source of Acquisition
      ML.2012.020
    - Eddy, Mary P, 1893-1927; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Biographical Information, 1882-1977; 1 box
    - Hoskins Genealogy, 1924; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Hoskins, Franklin E. and Hoskins, Harriette B, 1918-1923; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Hill School Records, circa 1910; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Princeton, 1913-1917; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - South American Trip, 1925; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - General, 1943-1969; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Obituaries, 1977; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Hoskins, Franklin E. and Hoskins, Harriette B, 1915-1929; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Barge Cruise and Europe Trips, 1972-1973; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Hoskins, Franklin E., Princeton Grades, 1882-1883; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Eddy, Mary P, 1900-1904; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - General, 1953-1955; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Personal Documentation, 1946-1970; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Travel Itineraries, 1965-1970; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Travel Brochures, 1972; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Princeton Papers, 1916-1918; 1 box
    - Jurisprudence, 1916-1917; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Chemistry, 1917; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Legislation, 1916-1917; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Government, 1916-1917; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - French Essays and Reports, 1916; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Bric-A-Brac, 1918; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Manuscripts, 1822-1982; 1 box
    - By Franklin E. Hoskins, circa 1880s; 4 folders (Box 9, Folder 30-33)
    - "Great Conflicts", undated; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Harriette Hoskins Scrapbook, circa 1885; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Photographs, 1822-1982; 3 boxes
    - Postcards and Souvenir Photographs, circa 1900; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Hoskins, Franklin E, undated; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Hoskins, Harriette E, undated; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Hoskins Children, undated; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Hoskins Family, 1871-1904; 3 folders (Box 10, Folder 5-7)
    - Missionary Life, circa 1883; 6 folders (Box 10, Folder 8-13)
    - Glass slides, undated; 1 box (Box 10)
    - Gold Pocket Watch, undated; 1 box (Box 10)
    - Oversize photographs, circa 1980; 1 box (Box 11)
    - Photographic Negatives of Cairo, Jiddha, Riyadh, Other Locations by Hoskins, circa 1943; 1 box 16mm safety film (Box 13)
- Series 3: 2014 Accession, 1885-1966; 4 boxes
  The 2014 accession is mainly comprised of photographs of Harold Hoskins's travels in the Middle East and his correspondence to his wife, Grania. To a lesser extent, it contains military documents from Hoskins's service in World War I and other documentation of his travels in the form of journals, postcards, and a map. Hoskins family photographs, personal correspondence related to the birth of Harold and Grania Hoskins's daughter, and a small amount of material on Harold Hoskins's father, Franklin Hoskins, is also included.
  - Travel journals and memorandum pocketbooks, 1939-1940, 1954-1957; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Franklin E. Hoskins papers, circa 1888-1920; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Harold B. Hoskins correspondence, 1895, 1918, 1946; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Franklin E. Hoskins letters from Beirut, 1885-1909; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Harold B. Hoskins correspondence, 1938-1957; 14 folders (Box 14, Folder 5-18)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1941-1942; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Harold B. Hoskins correspondence, circa 1941-1950; 2 folders (Box 14, Folder 20-21)
  - Near East Colleges publicity, 1945; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Harold B. Hoskins correspondence and printed material, circa 1948-1951; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Congratulatory letters to Mr. and Mrs. Harold Hoskins, 1946; 2 folders (Box 14, Folder 24-25)
  - Harold B. Hoskins correspondence, circa 1957; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Harold and Grania Hoskins letters from Tehran, 1944-1945; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Photographs of exterior of hospital, undated; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Panoramic photographs, undated; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Photographs from Harold Hoskins trip to Middle East, 1948; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - Harold Hoskins in Uniform, undated; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - Department of State Photographs, circa 1955-1957; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - Photographs of Harold Hoskins, circa 1939-1955; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - Photographs of Hoskins family, circa 1890 - 1917; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - German Postcards and Military Personnel Documents, circa 1916-1919; 2 folders (Box 15, Folder 1-2)
  - Trans-Jordan Government map of Kerak, undated; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Photographs of young Harold Hoskins and siblings, circa 1896-1917; 2 folders (Box 15, Folder 4-5)
  - Photographs of Harriet Eddy Hoskins, circa 1897 - 1927; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Photographs of Harold Hoskins and Grania Hoskins, circa 1942-1944; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Photographs of Harold Hoskins with friends outdoors, undated; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Photographs of exteriors of Middle Eastern countries, circa 1944-1956; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Postcards of the Monastery of Mount Sinai and other locations, undated; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Negatives, undated; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Oversize Photographs, undated; 1 box (Box 16)
  - Hamlin Memorial Sanatorium Photograph Album, 1953; 1 box (Box 16)
  - Foreign Service Institute Scrapbook, 1957-1966; 1 box (Box 16)
  - Awards and Certificates (rolled), 1913-1919; 1 box (Box 17)
  - Portraits of Hoskins Family, undated; 1 box (Box 17)
  - Photograph Album, circa 1944; 1 box (Box 17)
  - Photograph Album, undated; 1 box (Box 17)
  - Slides of Princeton Reunions and other events, circa 1955-1959; 1 box (Box 17)